The Leonard Shaw Papers RG.8
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
Guide to the Leonard Shaw Papers, 1978-1998
Bulk, 1978-1998
1978-2003
RG.8
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
1.0 Linear feet One box
Leonard Shaw served as Head of the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science from 1982 – 1990, then as the Dean of the School of EE and CS until 1994. Throughout his time both teaching and in his leadership roles, Shaw was an active member of the faculty, helping to plan and execute joint programs with institutions abroad in Iran and Italy, as well as courses offered in the Picatinny Arsenal in New Jersey and on the Brooklyn campus.
Shaw, Leonard
Box 1
Biographical/Historical note
Professor Leonard Shaw joined the faculty at Polytechnic University in 1960, where he taught Electrical Engineering (EE) for 43 years. During that time, Shaw also served as the Head of the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science from 1982- 1990, and then Dean of the School of EE and CS until 1994.
Arrangement note
Series are arranged by subject. Items are arranged chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Contents note
The Leonard Shaw Papers includes departmental records, memorandum, and correspondence concerning the Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Department from 1973 through 1999.
This collection documents the merger with NYU in 1973 and some of the effects on the EE/CS Department and students, primarily in regards to confusion surrounding graduation requirements. This collection also contains records from the departmental decision to eventually phase-out the evening course offerings for the BS in EE program in 1989. Also included in the collection are records of the planning, implementation, and assessment of joint EE degree programs offered in cooperation with both Reiss-Romoli in Italy in the early 1990s and the School of Television and Cinema in Tehran, Iran in the late 1970s. Lastly, the collection contains records of the National Science Foundation Graduate Research Traineeship from 1993 through 1999.
National Science Foundation (U.S.).; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.) -- Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; Scuola superiore guglielmo Reiss Romoli.; Computer science; Electrical engineering; Engineering; Memoranda; Merger - NYU-Poly - 1973; Picatinny Arsenal; Universities and colleges--Mergers--New York
- Series I: Polytechnic University and NYU Merger, 1973-1989 (Box 1)
  - Department of Electrical Engineering and Electrophysics, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Phase-out of Evening BS in EE Program, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Joint programs, 1978-1990 (Box 1)
  - Joint EE Program with School of Television and Cinema, Iran, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Joint MS Program with Reiss-Romoli, 1989- 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Joint MS Program with Reiss-Romoli, 1991- 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III: Graduate Programs, 1982-1999 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Courses at Picatinny Arsenal, NJ, 1982-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National Science Foundation Graduate Research Traineeship, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Science Foundation Graduate Traineeship Report, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Acquisition Note, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)